{
    "questions": [
        {
            "Question": "Hindu Mahasabha was founded in __________",
            "optionA": "  Thaneswar, Kannauj ",
            "optionB": "  Delhi, Deogiri ",
            "optionC": "  Kamboj, Kannauj ",
            "optionD": "  Valiabhi, Delhi ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tHindu Mahasabha was founded in Thaneswar, Kannauj. Harsha moved his capital from thaneswar to kannauj and ruled with his sister Rajyashree. ",
            "keyString": "598031s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Coins made of metal first appeared in",
            "optionA": "  Harappan Civilisation ",
            "optionB": "  Later Vedic Age ",
            "optionC": "  Age of the Buddha ",
            "optionD": "  Age of the Mauryas ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCoins made of metal first appeared in the age of Gautama Buddha. The earliest were made largely of silver though a few copper coins also appear. Coins made of burnt clay belong to the Kushan period i.e., the first three Christian centuries. ",
            "keyString": "598106s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The first Indian ruler, who established the supremacy of Indian Navy in the Arabian Sea was",
            "optionA": "  Rajaraja I ",
            "optionB": "  Rajendra I ",
            "optionC": "  Rajadhiraja I ",
            "optionD": "  Kulottunga I ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRajaraja I created a powerful standing army and a considerable navy. Chola king Raja raja-I maintained very large Navy. ",
            "keyString": "598130s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Mention the centre of the Roman trade during the Sangam Age",
            "optionA": "  Madurai ",
            "optionB": "  Arikamedu ",
            "optionC": "  Poompuhar ",
            "optionD": "  Musiri ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMusiri is a Historical city situated on the banks of the river Cauvery in the district of Trichy, Tamil Nadu. The city was ruled by The Chola king Musukundan and named after him as \u201cMusukundapuri\u201d in late 10th Century and was derived later as Musiri. There was a lot of export activity (Spices, Pearls, Medicinal Plants) From Tamil to Greece and Rome Musiri, Thondi, Puhar, Kumari, Konkai were the important Sea-ports. ",
            "keyString": "598149s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "St. Thomas is said to have come to India to propagate Christianity during the reign of the",
            "optionA": "  Cheras ",
            "optionB": "  Parthians ",
            "optionC": "  Pandyas ",
            "optionD": "  Cholas ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe most famous Shaka ruler in India was Rudradaman I (AD 130\u201350). The Parthians Shaka domination in north-western India was followed by Parithans in whose reign St Thomas is said to have come to India to propagate Christianity. St. Thomas came to India in the reign of Parthians. ",
            "keyString": "598166s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following option is matched?",
            "optionA": "  Ellora -- Shakas ",
            "optionB": "  Mahabalipuram -- Rashtrakuta ",
            "optionC": "  Meenakshi Temple -- Pallavas ",
            "optionD": "  Khajuraho -- Chandelas ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe right match is as follows- Ellora -Rashtrakutas Mahabalipuram - Pallavas Meenakshi - Pandyas & NayaksKhajuraho - Chandelas",
            "keyString": "641773s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Who was the first ruler of Pala dynasty?",
            "optionA": "  Gopala ",
            "optionB": "  Vivyanathan ",
            "optionC": "  Dharmapala ",
            "optionD": "  Bhaskaran ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPala dynasty, ruling dynasty in Bihar and Bengal, India, from the 8th to the 12th century. Its founder, Gopala, was a local chieftain who rose to power in the mid-8th century during a period of anarchy. ",
            "keyString": "641855s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Of the four main Chalukya dynasties of early medieval India Pulakesin II, who defeated Harsha, belonged to Chalukya dynasty of",
            "optionA": "  Anhilwad (Gujarat) ",
            "optionB": "  Badami or Vatapi ",
            "optionC": "  Vengi ",
            "optionD": "  Kalyani ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Chalukya dynasty was an Indian royal dynasty that ruled large parts of southern and central India between the 6th and the 12th centuries. During this period, they ruled as three related yet individual dynasties. The earliest dynasty, known as the \"Badami Chalukyas\", ruled from Vatapi (modern Badami) from the middle of the 6th century. The Badami Chalukyas began to assert their independence at the decline of the Kadamba kingdom of Banavasi and rapidly rose to prominence during the reign of Pulakeshin II.",
            "keyString": "641882s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which Sangam literature was composed by Jain monks and the theme is the transient nature of life and youth?",
            "optionA": "  Nanmanikkatiga ",
            "optionB": "  Naaladiyar ",
            "optionC": "  Inna Narpathu ",
            "optionD": "  Iniyavai Narpathu ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNaaladiyar was composed by Jain monks and the theme is the transient nature of life and youth. It was work of Nalatiyar. ",
            "keyString": "641905s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Chalukya temples (Jain temples) at Dilwara are situated in",
            "optionA": "  Madhya Pradesh ",
            "optionB": "  Uttar Pradesh ",
            "optionC": "  Rajasthan ",
            "optionD": "  Haryana ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLocated near Mount Abu in Rajasthan, Dilwara temples comprise of five Jain temples that are known for its religious and architectural significance. Built between 11th and 13th centuries AD, these temples are one of the finest examples of temples during the reign of Chalukya dynasty. Dilwara Temples are situated near Mount Abu. ",
            "keyString": "641925s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which Chola king founded the city of Puhar?",
            "optionA": "  Rajendra Chola ",
            "optionB": "  Ellara ",
            "optionC": "  Senguttavan ",
            "optionD": "  Karikala ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPuhar is a town of Tamil Nadu. It is also known as Kaveripatnam. It was founded by Chola King Karikala Puhar served as the capital of the early Chola kings. Karikala was a Tamil Chola king who ruled southern India. He is attributed to the conquest of the whole of India up to the Himalayas and the construction of the flood banks of the river Kaveri. He is recognised as the greatest of the Early Cholas. ",
            "keyString": "682893s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Where is the Brihadeshwar temple built during  the Chola period located?",
            "optionA": "  Mysore ",
            "optionB": "  Mahabalipuram ",
            "optionC": "  Thanjavur ",
            "optionD": "  Kanyakumari ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBrihadeshwar temple is located Thanjavur in the Indian state of Tamil Nadu. It is also known as Periya Kovil, RajaRajeswara Temple and Rajarajeswaram. It is one of the largest temples in India. Brihadeshwara is an example of Hindu architecture from South India from the Chola period. ",
            "keyString": "682930s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Uttaramerur inscription provides information of the administration of the",
            "optionA": "  Chalukyas ",
            "optionB": "  Satavahanas ",
            "optionC": "  Pallavas ",
            "optionD": "  Cholas ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Chola kings followed a highly efficient system of' administration. The most important feature of the Chola administration was the local administration at districts, towns and villages level. Uttaramerur inscriptions speak much about the Chola administration. ",
            "keyString": "682948s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "During the Sangam Age brisk and nourishing foreign trade was conducted from the south Indian ports of Muziris, Kaveripattnam or Poom-Puhar and Arikamedu to",
            "optionA": "  West Asia ",
            "optionB": "  South East Asia ",
            "optionC": "  Roman World ",
            "optionD": "  Central Europe ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDuring, Sangam Age brisk and nourishing foreign trade was conducted from the south Indian ports of Muziris, Kaveripattnam or Poom-Puhar and Arikamedu to Roman World. ",
            "keyString": "682964s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The masterpiece of Chola sculpture is the famous Nataraja or the Dancing Shiva image at",
            "optionA": "  Thanjavur ",
            "optionB": "  Chidambaram ",
            "optionC": "  Kalahasti ",
            "optionD": "  Sri Sailam ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Cholas also encouraged plastic art; the metal and stone images cast during the period are exquisitely executed and display a wonderful vigour, diginity and grace. The masterpiece of Chola sculpture is the famous Natraja or the Dancing Shiva image at the great temple of Chidambaram. The Nataraja has been described as the \"cutura epitome\" of the Chola period. ",
            "keyString": "682978s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Beetapala and Dhiman, the two great artists that India had produced, belonged to the",
            "optionA": "  Pala Age ",
            "optionB": "  Gupta Age ",
            "optionC": "  Maurya Age ",
            "optionD": "  Pathan Age ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBeetapala and Dhiman, the two great artists that India had produced, belonged to the Pala Age. ",
            "keyString": "741708s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which dynasty succeeded the Chalukyas in the Western India?",
            "optionA": "  Cholas ",
            "optionB": "  Kakatiyas ",
            "optionC": "  Pallavas ",
            "optionD": "  Rashtrakutas ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Chalukya dynasty was an Indian royal dynasty that ruled large parts of southern and central India between the 6th and the 12th centuries. The earliest dynasty, known as the 'Badami Chalukyas', ruled from Vatapi (modern Badami) from the middle of the 6th century. The Badami Chalukyas began to assert their independence at the decline of the Kadamba kingdom of Banavasi and rapidly rose to prominence during the reign of Pulakesin II. After the death of Pulakesin II, the Eastern Chalukyas became an independent kingdom in the eastern Deccan. They ruled from Vengi until about the 11th century. In the western Deccan, the rise of the Rashtrakutas in the middle of the 8th century eclipsed the Chalukyas of Badami before being revived by their descendants, the Western Chalukyas, in the late 10th century.",
            "keyString": "741868s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Harshvardhana was defeated by",
            "optionA": "  Prabhakaravardhana ",
            "optionB": "  Pulakesin II ",
            "optionC": "  Narshimvarman ",
            "optionD": "  Sasanka ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPulakeshin II defeated Harsha on the banks of Narmada in the winter of 618-619 CE. Pulakeshin entered into a treaty with Harsha, with the Narmada River designated as the border between the Chalukya Empire and that of Harshavardhana. ",
            "keyString": "742193s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "After the decline of the Chalukya kingdom of Kalyani at the close of the 12th and of the Chola kingdom at the beginning of the 13th century, the new kingdoms which arose in South India were",
            "optionA": "  Yadavas of Devagiri and Kakatiyas of Warangal ",
            "optionB": "  Hoysalas of Dwarsamudra and Pandyas of Madurai ",
            "optionC": "  Vijayanagar and Bahamani kingdoms ",
            "optionD": "  Both A and B above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAfter the decline of the Chalukya kingdom of Kalyani at the close of the 12th and of the Chola kingdom at the beginning of the 13th century, the new kingdoms which arose in South India were Yadavas of Devagiri and Kakatiyas of Warangal and Hoysalas of Dwarsamudra and Pandyas of Madurai. ",
            "keyString": "742462s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following was the capital of the Chola Kings?",
            "optionA": "  Kanchi ",
            "optionB": "  Tanjore ",
            "optionC": "  Madurai ",
            "optionD": "  Trichurapally ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThanjavur became the capital of the Imperial Chola Dynasty. Vijayalaya was the founder of Chola dynasty. He captured Tanjore in 850 A.D.",
            "keyString": "742725s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following was not one of the ruling dynasties of South India in the Sangam Age?",
            "optionA": "  Chola ",
            "optionB": "  Chera ",
            "optionC": "  Pandya ",
            "optionD": "  Pallava ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Pandyas were one of the three ancient Tamil dynasties (Chola and Chera being the other two) who ruled the Tamil country from pre-historic times until the end of the 15th century. They ruled initially from Korkai, a seaport on the southernmost tip of the Indian peninsula, and in later times moved to Madurai. ",
            "keyString": "800944s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The school of Indian art which is also known as the Greek-Roman-Buddhist art is the__________school",
            "optionA": "  Mauryan ",
            "optionB": "  Shunga ",
            "optionC": "  Gandhar ",
            "optionD": "  Gupta ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGandhara art, style of Buddhist visual art that developed in what is now northwestern Pakistan and eastern Afghanistan between the 1st century bce and the 7th century ce. The style, of Greco-Roman origin, seems to have flourished largely during the Kushan dynasty and was contemporaneous with an important but dissimilar school of Kushan art at Mathura (Uttar Pradesh, India). ",
            "keyString": "801068s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The ancient Chola kingdom existed in the delta of the river",
            "optionA": "  Tungabhadra ",
            "optionB": "  Cauvery ",
            "optionC": "  Krishna ",
            "optionD": "  Godavari ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Chola dynasty was one of the longest-ruling dynasties in history. The heartland of the Cholas was the fertile valley of the Kaveri River. ",
            "keyString": "801101s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Arabs were defeated in 738 A.D. by",
            "optionA": "  Pratiharas ",
            "optionB": "  Chalukyas ",
            "optionC": "  Both A and B together ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Battle of Rajasthan is a battle (or series of battles) where the Gurjar Hindu alliance defeated the Arab invaders in 738 CEThe final battle took place somewhere on the borders of modern Sindh-Rajasthan. Following their defeat the remnants of the Arab army fled to the other bank of the River Indus.The main Indian kings who contributed to the victory over the Arabs were the north Indian Gurjar Emperor Nagabhata I of the Pratihara Dynasty and the south Indian Gurjar Emperor Vikramaditya II of the Chalukya dynasty in the 8th century.Source : thehistoryindia.blogspot.com ",
            "keyString": "801126s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statement (s) is/are not correct about the Sangam literature?",
            "optionA": "  The Sangam literature describes many kings and dynasties of South India ",
            "optionB": "  The Sangam literature describes many kings and dynasties of North India ",
            "optionC": "  Sangama is compilation of poems by group of poets of different times patronised by many chiefs and kings ",
            "optionD": "  Both\u00a0B & C ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Sangam literature does not describes many kings and dynasties of North India. ",
            "keyString": "801146s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Who were the patrons of Sangama Literature?",
            "optionA": "  Nayakas ",
            "optionB": "  Chandellas ",
            "optionC": "  Pandyas ",
            "optionD": "  Solankis ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSangam was the ancient academy, which enabled Tamil poets and authors to gather periodically to publish their work. The Sangam met periodically in the city of Madurai in South India under the patronage of the Pandya kings. The current estimate is that the Sangam period lasted between 400 BCE until 300 CE. ",
            "keyString": "851293s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following Chola Kings conquered Ceylon (Singhal) first?",
            "optionA": "  Aditya - I ",
            "optionB": "  Rajaraja - I ",
            "optionC": "  Rajendra Chola ",
            "optionD": "  Vijayalya ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRajaraja -I conquered Ceylon (Singhal) first. The period of Chola rule in the island of Sri Lanka began with the invasion in 993 AD, when Raja Raja Chola sent a large Chola army which conquered the Anuradhapura Kingdom, in the north, and added it to the Chola Empire. ",
            "keyString": "851344s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The most distinguished ruler of the Chalukyan dynasty was",
            "optionA": "  Jayasimha II ",
            "optionB": "  Vikrarnaditya VI ",
            "optionC": "  Somesvara II ",
            "optionD": "  Pulakesin II ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPulakeshin II (610-642 CE) was the most famous ruler of the Chalukya dynasty of Vatapi (present-day Badami in Karnataka, India). During his reign, the Chalukya kingdom expanded to cover most of the Deccan region in peninsular India. ",
            "keyString": "851359s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is one of the greatest classics of the Sangam literature?",
            "optionA": "  Tikappiyam ",
            "optionB": "  Kural ",
            "optionC": "  Pattuppattu ",
            "optionD": "  Silapadikaram or Manimekalai ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tManimekalai mentions the collaboration of architects from Maharashtra, blacksmiths from Malwa, carpenters from Greece and Rome and jewellers from Magadha with their counterparts of the Tamil region. The occupation or profession was generally hereditary or handed down from father to the son. According to Silappadikaram, men of different occupation lived in different streets. This led to progress in various trades and industries and also resulted in making these men skilled in their art. The art of building reached a high level during this period. In this context the works of carpenters are noteworthy. This can be observed in the use of boats with face of the horse, elephant and lion mentioned by Silappadikaram. ",
            "keyString": "851607s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not true about Ajanta Caves?",
            "optionA": "  They are in Maharashtra ",
            "optionB": "  They are decorated with Buddhist Art ",
            "optionC": "  They depict the techniques used in Ancient\nIndia ",
            "optionD": "  They do not contain paintings of flora and fauna ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAjanta Caves does not depict the techniques usedin Ancient India. ",
            "keyString": "851628s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "According to the categories of land mentioned in the Chola inscriptions __________ was known as the land gifted to Brahmanas?",
            "optionA": "  Vellanvagai ",
            "optionB": "  Brahmadeya ",
            "optionC": "  Shalabhoga ",
            "optionD": "  Devadana ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBrahmadeya - land gifted to Brahmanas in Chola's period. ",
            "keyString": "904570s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Chola ruler who had subdued the Ganges and obtained the title 'Gangai Konda Cholan' was",
            "optionA": "  Rajaraja Chola ",
            "optionB": "  Rajendra Chola I ",
            "optionC": "  Rajadhiraja Chola ",
            "optionD": "  Kulattunga ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo commemorate his celebrated northern campaign to the Ganges, Rajendra assumed the title of Gangaikonda Chola and had the Siva Temple Gangakkondacholeswaram built. Soon after, he moved the capital from Thanjavur to Gangaikondacholapuram. Rajendra probably founded the city of Gangaikondacholapuram before his 17th year. Most of the Chola kings who succeeded Rajendra had been crowned in Gangakkondacholeswaram. They retained it as their capital, reoriented and trained the efficient Chola army. ",
            "keyString": "904604s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Sangam Age in the history of South India represents",
            "optionA": "  The period of Aryanisation of South India ",
            "optionB": "  A period when an assembly of a college of Tamil poets was held at Madurai ",
            "optionC": "  A literary-cultural phase of the Tamilham during the first three centuries of the Christian era ",
            "optionD": "  Both B and C above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThat women belonging to the Sangam Age were educated, is clearly obvious from the fact that the Sangam literature consist of many poems written by women poets. The most remarkable feature of the Sangam literature is its vivid description of the contemporary society and culture of Tamilaham or Tamil region and its harmonious and peaceful interaction with the Aryan (northern) culture. Poems representing the Sangam Literature were authored on two broader themes of love and war. ",
            "keyString": "904618s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Rashtrakuta kingdom was founded by",
            "optionA": "  Danti Durga (Danti Varman) ",
            "optionB": "  Amoghavarsh ",
            "optionC": "  Govinda III ",
            "optionD": "  Indra III ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Elichpur clan was a feudatory of the Badami Chalukyas, and during the rule of Dantidurga, it overthrew Chalukya Kirtivarman II and went on to build an empire with the Gulbarga region in modern Karnataka as its base. This clan came to be known as the Rashtrakutas of Manyakheta, rising to power in South India in 753. ",
            "keyString": "904630s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the Mehrauli Pillar in the complex of Qutub Minar Primarily famous for?",
            "optionA": "  Proverbial height ",
            "optionB": "  Skilful stone cutting ",
            "optionC": "  Excellent quality steel ",
            "optionD": "  Statue of Buddha on top ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMehrauli Pillar is famous for Excellent quality steel because its high resistance to corrosion and has been called a \"testimony to the high level of skill achieved by the ancient Indian iron smiths in the extraction and processing of iron\". The corrosion resistance results from an even layer of crystalline iron hydrogen phosphate hydrate forming on the high-phosphorus-content iron, which serves to protect it from the effects of the Delhi climate. ",
            "keyString": "904642s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The chief feature(s) of the Chola architecture was/were",
            "optionA": "  replacement of bricks by stone structure ",
            "optionB": "  massive vimanas or towers ",
            "optionC": "  temples became vast complexes ",
            "optionD": "  spacious courtyards ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVimana is the structure over the garbhagriha or inner sanctum in the Hindu temples of South India and Odisha in East India. In typical temples of Odisha using the Kalinga style of architecture, the Vimana is the tallest structure of the temple, as it is in the shikhara towers of temples in West and North India. ",
            "keyString": "956394s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "During the reign of which Pallava ruler began the long drawn struggle between the Pallavas\nand the Chalukyas?",
            "optionA": "  Mahendravarman-I ",
            "optionB": "  Simhavishnu ",
            "optionC": "  Narasimhavarman-I ",
            "optionD": "  Mahendravarman-II ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPallavas became a major power during the reign of Mahendravarma I (571 \u2013 630 CE) and Narasimhavarma I (630 \u2013 668 CE) and dominated the Telugu and northern parts of the Tamil region for about 600 years until the end of the 9th century. Throughout their reign they were in constant conflict with both Chalukyas of Badami in the north and the Tamil kingdoms of Chola and Pandyas in the south and Pallava were finally defeated by the Chola Aditya I in the 9th century CE. ",
            "keyString": "956429s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does the Sangam age owe its name to?",
            "optionA": "  Village assembly ",
            "optionB": "  Jain Influence ",
            "optionC": "  Confluence of rivers ",
            "optionD": "  A literary guild ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t The Sangam means an 'association'. Here, it refers to Tamil Sangam, an association of Tamil poets, which flourished in ancient history of South India. These Tamil poets composed the Sangam literature and the period in which it was composed is called Sangam Age. ",
            "keyString": "956443s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Cholas were the only known rulers in the history of India to have undertaken successful overseas naval expeditions. Who of the following Chola rulers successfully invaded Laccadives, Maldives, Sri Lanka and Sumatra?",
            "optionA": "  Parantaka-I ",
            "optionB": "  Rajaraja-I ",
            "optionC": "  Rajendra-I ",
            "optionD": "  Both B & C above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRajendra Chola I or Rajendra I was a Chola emperor of South India (Present day Tamilnadu, Andhra pradesh, Kerala, Part of karnataka and Telangana) who succeeded his father Rajaraja Chola I to the throne in 1014 CE. He is considered as one of the greatest emperors of India. During his reign, he extended the influence of the Chola empire to the banks of the river Ganga in North India and across the Indian ocean to the West and South East Asia, making the Chola Empire one of the most powerful empires of India. Rajendra\u2019s conquests included Sri Lanka, Maldives, and he successfully invaded the territories of Srivijaya in Malaysia, Southern Thailand and Indonesia in South East Asia. ",
            "keyString": "956456s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Ravikirti, a Jain, who composed the Aihole Prashasti, was patronized by -",
            "optionA": "  Pulakeshin-I ",
            "optionB": "  Harsha ",
            "optionC": "  Pulakeshin-II ",
            "optionD": "  Kharavela ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe inscription is found at Aihole in Karnataka state, India. The Aihole inscription was written by the Ravikirti, court poet of Chalukya King, Pulakeshi II who reigned from 610 to 642 CE. The poetic verses (Shilalekh) of Ravikirti, in praise of the king, can be read in the Meguti temple, dated 634 CE. ",
            "keyString": "956468s39m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The achievements of Samudragupta have been chronicled in the",
            "optionA": "  Hathigumpha inscription ",
            "optionB": "  Sarnath inscription ",
            "optionC": "  Girnar inscription ",
            "optionD": "  Allahabad pillar inscription ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Allahabad Pillar Inscriptions of Samudra Gupta provide information regarding the achievements of the ruler. ",
            "keyString": "16598s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The capital of Pallavas was",
            "optionA": "  Areot ",
            "optionB": "  Kanchi ",
            "optionC": "  Malkhed ",
            "optionD": "  Banacasi ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Pallava dynasty was founded by Pallava Simhavishnu during the late 6th century Kanchi (Kanchipuram). Tamil Nadu Served as their capital. Kanchipuram is also known as 'the religious capital of the south'. ",
            "keyString": "16632s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A contemporary rival dynasty of the Cholas in South India was",
            "optionA": "  Chalukyas of Vengi ",
            "optionB": "  Pandyas of Madurai ",
            "optionC": "  Chalukyas of Kalyani ",
            "optionD": "  Cheras ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe decline of the Chalukya kingdom of Kalyani at the close of the 12th century. ",
            "keyString": "16647s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The bronze coins of Natraja or Dancing Shiva during the Chola period invariably depicted the deity with __________ arms",
            "optionA": "  Eight ",
            "optionB": "  Six ",
            "optionC": "  Four ",
            "optionD": "  Two ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe bronze coins of Natraja or Dancing Shiva during the Chola period invariably depicted the deity with six arms. ",
            "keyString": "16659s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Hoysala's capital was",
            "optionA": "  Warangal ",
            "optionB": "  Devagiri ",
            "optionC": "  Dwarasamudra ",
            "optionD": "  Krishnagiri ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t \u201cDwarasamudra\u201d capital of Hoysala dynasty who ruled the Karnataka area of south India between 10 and 14th centuries. Initially its capital was bellur and later it was moved to Halebidu (Dwarasamudra).",
            "keyString": "16670s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which Chola ruler had conquered the northern part of Sri Lanka and made it a province of his empire?",
            "optionA": "  Rajindra Chola I ",
            "optionB": "  Adhirajindra Chola ",
            "optionC": "  Parantaka Chola I ",
            "optionD": "  Rajaraja Chola I ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTaking advantage of a civil war which had caused the Sinhalese monarch Mahinda V to flee to the south-east province of Anuradhapura known as Ruhuna, Raja Raja Chola invaded Anuradhapura sometime between 991 and 993 AD and conquered the northern part of the country and incorporated it into his kingdom as a province. ",
            "keyString": "83798s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Name the capital of the Pallavas?",
            "optionA": "  Kanchi ",
            "optionB": "  Vatapi ",
            "optionC": "  Trichurapalli ",
            "optionD": "  Mahabalipuram ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Tamil country was divided between the Pallavas in the north with Kanchipuram as their capital, and Pandyas in the south with Madurai as their capital.It is also known as \"the city of Thousand Temples.\" ",
            "keyString": "83946s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The lowest unit of Chola administration was the",
            "optionA": "  Kottam ",
            "optionB": "  Mandalam ",
            "optionC": "  Kurram ",
            "optionD": "  Valanadu ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tKurram was the lowest unit of Chola administration. ",
            "keyString": "83986s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Who was the Chola king who brought Ganga from North to South?",
            "optionA": "  Raja Raja Chola ",
            "optionB": "  Mahendra ",
            "optionC": "  Rajendra Chola ",
            "optionD": "  Pararrtaka ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAfter defeating the Pala kingdom, King Rajendra Chola came back south, bringing with him water from the Ganges. He built a new city and called it \u2018Gangaikonda Cholapuram\u2019 \u2013 The city of the Chola who brought the Ganges. He built a Shiva temple in the city, rivaling the one his father built in Thanjavur. He built a 22 km wide artificial lake near the city. He shifted the Chola capital from Thanjavur.",
            "keyString": "84000s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Chalukya king Pulakesin-II was defeated by",
            "optionA": "  Mahendra Varman-I ",
            "optionB": "  Narasimha Varman-I ",
            "optionC": "  Parameswara Verman-I ",
            "optionD": "  Jatila Parantaka ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNarasimha ruled between 645 and 670 AD. During his rule he was able to establish the dominance of the Pallava Empire in the South. He was an excellent war strategist. He defeated Pulakesin II and destroyed the Chalukyan capital, Vatapi.",
            "keyString": "84012s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following Inscriptions related to the Chalukya king, Pulakesin-II?",
            "optionA": "  Maski ",
            "optionB": "  Hathigumpha ",
            "optionC": "  Aihole ",
            "optionD": "  Nasik ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAihole in Karnataka state, India, is known as Cradle of Indian architecture. It was the first capital of Chalukyas where they built numerous temples dating back to the 6th century CE.The Aihole inscription were written by the court poet and minister Ravi Kirti of Chalukyan king Pulakesin-II. ",
            "keyString": "126788s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "From which modern State did the Alwar saints orignate?",
            "optionA": "  Tamil Nadu ",
            "optionB": "  Kerala ",
            "optionC": "  Karnataka ",
            "optionD": "  Maharashtra ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFirst view is that it originated in Tamil Nadu during the seventh century and then spread through Karnataka, Maharashtra and spread in almost all parts of Northern / Eastern India by 15th century. In Tamil Nadu, the movement was started by Vaishnava saints {Alvars} and Shaiva saints {Nayanars}",
            "keyString": "126889s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "According to the categories of land mentioned in the Chola inscriptions __________ was known as the land donated to Jain institutions?",
            "optionA": "  Vellanvagai ",
            "optionB": "  Brahmadeya ",
            "optionC": "  Shalabhoga ",
            "optionD": "  Pallichchhandarn ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t Pallichchhandam - land donated to Jaina institutions.",
            "keyString": "126920s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following Sangam Text is the collection of 100 songs of Vilambi Naganaar and deals conditions / emotions of 4 types of people who cannot sleep in the night and they are thief, lovelorn, after money, and worrying about losing money?",
            "optionA": "  Nanmanikkatiga ",
            "optionB": "  Acharakkovai ",
            "optionC": "  Thirikatukam ",
            "optionD": "  Kalavazhi Narpathu ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNanmanikkatiga is the collection of 100 songs of Vilambi Naganaar and deals conditions / emotions of 4 types of people who cannot sleep in the night and they are thief, lovelorn, after money, and worrying about losing money.",
            "keyString": "126946s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Chola kings were ruling over",
            "optionA": "  Tamil Nadu ",
            "optionB": "  Andhra ",
            "optionC": "  Kerala ",
            "optionD": "  Bengal ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Chola dynasty (850 - 1279 A.D) was one of the longest ruling dynasties of south India with their capital at Tanjor (Tamil Nadu). It was founded by Vijayalya. ",
            "keyString": "126971s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Chola king, who after successfully raiding Bengal took the title of Gangaikonda and also founded a new capital (Gangaikonda Cholapuram) was",
            "optionA": "  Rajaraja-I ",
            "optionB": "  Rajendra-I ",
            "optionC": "  Rajadhiraj-I ",
            "optionD": "  Rajendra-II ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRajendra Chola I or Rajendra I was a Chola emperor of South India who succeeded his father Rajaraja Chola I to the throne in 1014 CE. He is considered as one of the greatest emperors of India. ",
            "keyString": "172979s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "During the second decade of the 18th century numerous independent dynasties were founded in different parts of India. The dynasty founded by Chin Qulich Khan (popularly known as Nizam-u1-mulk) in the Deccan was known as",
            "optionA": "  Qutb Shahi ",
            "optionB": "  Asafjahi ",
            "optionC": "  Adil Shahi ",
            "optionD": "  Muhajamjahi ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Asaf Jahi Dynasty was founded by Mir Qamar-ud-Din Siddiqi, a viceroy of the Deccan under the Mughal Empire from 1713 to 1721. He is also known by his titles Chin Qilich Khan (awarded by emperor Aurangzeb in 1690\u201391).",
            "keyString": "173013s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How was Burma (now Myanmar) known to ancient Indians?",
            "optionA": "  Malayamandalam ",
            "optionB": "  Yavadwipa ",
            "optionC": "  Suvarnabhumi ",
            "optionD": "  Suvarnadwipa ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSuvarnabhumi is a Sanskrit term meaning the 'Golden Land' or 'Land of Gold', coined by the ancient Indians which refers broadly to Southeast Asian region across Gulf of Bengal and Eastern Indian Ocean, Lower Burma, Lower Thailand, Lower Malay Peninsula, and Sumatra. Although it seems to cover vast region in Southeast Asia, it is generally accepted that the name Suvarnabhumi was first used to refer more specifically to Lower Burma. ",
            "keyString": "173026s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Who was the contemporary South Indian ruler of Harshavardhana?",
            "optionA": "  Krishnadevaraya ",
            "optionB": "  Pulakesin II ",
            "optionC": "  Mayuravarma ",
            "optionD": "  Chikkadevaraja Wodeyar ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen Pulakesin II emerged as the undisputed master of the entire South, Emperor Harshavardhana was seen as the sovereign monarch of the entire North. Having established his supremacy on northern India, Harsha turned his attention towards the land beyond the Vindhyas. ",
            "keyString": "173038s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In Tamil literature the glorious books 'Shilppadikaram and Manimekalai' are related to",
            "optionA": "  Jainism ",
            "optionB": "  Buddhism ",
            "optionC": "  Hinduism ",
            "optionD": "  Christianity ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tManimekalai, by the poet Chithalai Chathanar, is one of The Five Great Epics of Tamil Literature according to later Tamil literary tradition. Silappadikaram is one of Five Great Epics according to later Tamil literary tradition. Manekalai was written by the Buddhist poet Chithalai Chathanar in post-Sangam era. The book describes Dharma, as the most perfect religion. Silappadikarma is a great Tamil epic written by a Jain poet prince Llano Adigal.Llango Adigal was a Buddhist monk and Silappadhikaram and Manimekalai are Buddhist epics.",
            "keyString": "173051s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following statement is/are correct?\nI. Pulakesn I was the first ruler of the Chalukya dynasty?\nII. Harshavardhana attacked the Chalukya territory during 608-642 AD?\nIII. Vikramaditya I died in 608 A.D",
            "optionA": "  All are correct ",
            "optionB": "  Only I ",
            "optionC": "  Only II,III ",
            "optionD": "  Only I, III ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPulakesn I was the first ruler of the Chalukya dynasty. The earliest dynasty, known as the \"Badami Chalukyas\", ruled from Vatapi (modern Badami) from the middle of the 6th century. After the death of Pulakeshin II, the Eastern Chalukyas became an independent kingdom in the eastern Deccan. They ruled from Vengi until about the 11th century. ",
            "keyString": "210183s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Pulakesin-II was the greatest ruler of the",
            "optionA": "  Cholas of Tamil Nadu ",
            "optionB": "  Chalukyas of Badami ",
            "optionC": "  Chalukyas Kalyani ",
            "optionD": "  Pallavas of Kanchi ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPulakeshin II (610-642 CE) was the most famous ruler of the Chalukya dynasty of Vatapi (present-day Badami in Karnataka, India). ... A son of the Chalukya king Kirttivarman I, Pulakeshin overthrew his uncle Mangalesha to gain control of the throne. ",
            "keyString": "210218s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following was the early capital of the Rashtrakutas?",
            "optionA": "  Sopara ",
            "optionB": "  Ellora ",
            "optionC": "  Vatapi ",
            "optionD": "  Ajanta ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSince most of the Rashtrakutas monuments are found at Ellora, with nothing correspondence at Malkhed (Manyakher), it has been suggested that the early capital was located in the vicinity of the Ellora caves in the time of Dantidurga who was the founder and first ruler of the dynasty. ",
            "keyString": "210232s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What was the capital of the early Chalukyas?",
            "optionA": "  Badami ",
            "optionB": "  Kalyani ",
            "optionC": "  Kanchi ",
            "optionD": "  Vengi ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDuring this period, they ruled as three related, but individual dynasties. The earliest dynasty, known as the \"Badami Chalukyas\", ruled from their capital Vatapi (modern Badami) from the middle of the 6th century. ",
            "keyString": "294950s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Sangam Age is associated with the history of",
            "optionA": "  Benaras ",
            "optionB": "  Allahabad ",
            "optionC": "  Tamil Nadu ",
            "optionD": "  Khajuraho ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSangam Period - 300 BC - 200 AD. The Sangam Age constitutes an important chapter in the history of South India. According to Tamil legends, there existed three Sangams (Academy of Tamil poets) in ancient Tamil Nadu popularly called Muchchangam. These Sangams flourished under the royal patronage of the Pandyas. ",
            "keyString": "294983s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "According to the categories of land mentioned in the Chola inscriptions __________ was known as the land gifted to temples?",
            "optionA": "  Vellanvagai ",
            "optionB": "  Brahmadeya ",
            "optionC": "  Shalabhoga ",
            "optionD": "  Devadana ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDevadana was the land gifted to temples. ",
            "keyString": "294997s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "According to the categories of land mentioned in the Chola inscriptions __________ was known as the land of non-Brahmana peasant proprietors?",
            "optionA": "  Vellanvagai ",
            "optionB": "  Brahmadeya ",
            "optionC": "  Shalabhoga ",
            "optionD": "  Devadana ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVellanvagai - land of non-Brahmana peasant proprietors. ",
            "keyString": "295009s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the present name of Dwara Samudra, the ancient capital of the Hoysalas?",
            "optionA": "  Mathura ",
            "optionB": "  Halebid ",
            "optionC": "  Raourkela ",
            "optionD": "  Belur ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe capital of the Hoysalas was initially located at Belur but was later moved to Halebid. The Hoysala rulers were originally from Malenadu, an elevated region in the Western Ghats. ",
            "keyString": "295022s40m11h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        }
    ]
}